好吧  我要调动我的步兵师
All right! I'm moving my infantry division.
从指环王里的兽人营加过来的
Augmented by battalion of orcs from lord of the rings.
我们从侧翼包围了田纳西的志愿兵
We flank the tennessee volunteers
而在北方  我们又一次赢得了葛底斯堡战役
And the north, once again, wins the battle of gettysburg.
没这么快!
Not so fast!
别忘了  南方还有两个步兵师
Remember, the south still has two infantry divisions,
再加上超人和哥斯拉
Plus superman and godzilla.
不  兽人会魔法  超人对魔法无能为力
No, orcs are magic. superman is vulnerable to magic.
更何况你的哥斯拉已经输给了伊利诺伊骑兵和绿巨人
Not to mention you already lost godzilla to the illinois cavalry and hulk.
为什么你不让罗伯特·李(美国南北战争南军统帅)
Why don't you just let robert e lee.
还有希瓦和伽内喜来统领这一线?
charge the line with shiva and ganesh?
-你们准备好点菜了吗  -稍等  亲爱的
-you guys ready to order? -hang on, honey.
希瓦和伽内喜?
Shiva and ganesh,
你要用印度教的神来对抗整个北方部队?
The hindu gods, against the entire union army?
还有兽人
And orcs.
我马上回来
I'll be back.
各位
Excuse me.
伽内喜能扫除一切障碍  而希瓦能摧毁一切
Ganesh is the remover of obstacles and shiva is the destroyer.
当浓烟散尽  亚伯拉罕·林肯会一边说印度语
When the smoke clears, abraham lincoln will be speaking hindi
一边喝着薄荷朱丽浦
And drinking mint juleps.
我老板说要么点菜  要么出去再也别回来
My boss says you have to either order or leave and never come back.
对于一位胃口巨大且刚结束晨间力量训练
What do you recommend for someone who worked up a man-sized appetite
和有氧热舞的人  你有什么推荐?
From a morning of weight training and cardio funk?
冲个澡
A shower.
我要慧心拼盘
I'll take the heart smart platter.
好的  谢谢  谢尔顿呢
All right, thank you, and sheldon?
我们没在这里吃过  我不清楚哪个好
We don't eat here. I don't know what's good.
-都不错  -从统计学来说不太可能
-it's all good. -statistically unlikely.
就要个汉堡吧  你喜欢吃汉堡的
Just get a hamburger. you like hamburgers.
平常我们吃的那些地方的汉堡我喜欢
I like hamburgers where we usually have them.
但你不能假定说这里的我也喜欢
You can't make the assumption that I'll like them here.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-给他来个汉堡  -哪一种
-give him a hamburger. -which one?
至尊汉堡  乡村汉堡
The classic burger, the ranch house burger,
烧烤汉堡  还是科比汉堡
The barbecue burger, or the kobe burger?
我们去"大块头"吃吧
Can't we just go to big boy?
他们那只有一种汉堡..."大块头"
They only have one burger... the big boy.
烧烤汉堡和"大块头"差不多
The barbecue burger's like the big boy.
不好意思  既然这个世界上已经有了"大块头"
Excuse me, in a world that already includes a big boy,
我为什么还要找个像"大块头"的
Why would I settle for something like a big boy?
因为你不在"大块头"!
Because you're not at big boy!
-好  我要个烧烤汉堡  -来两个
-fine, I'll have the barbecue burger. -make it two.
"大块头"里的女服务生从来不对人嚷嚷
Waitresses don't yell at you at big boy.
好  里奥纳德  大家好
Hey, leonard. hi, guys.
好  莱斯莉
Hi, leslie.
我不知道你在这里吃的啊
I didn't know you ate here.
我们不是  这次是令人不快的失误
We don't. this is a disturbing aberration.
莱斯莉  这位是潘妮
Leslie, this is penny.
她就住我和谢尔顿楼道对面
She lives across the hall from sheldon and me.
并且走起路来如夜一般安静和美丽
And walks in quiet beauty like the night.
霍华德  我已经让你不要这样了
Howard, I've asked you not to do that.
我和莱斯莉在大学里一起搞研究的
Leslie and I do research together at the university.
女科学家啊
Wow, a girl scientist.
没错  勾人靠胸部  留人靠头脑啊
Yep, come for the breasts, stay for the brains.
真高兴撞到了你
Glad I ran into you.
物理系弦乐四重奏需要一个新的大提琴手
The physics department string quartet needs a new cellist.
艾利奥特·王呢
What happened to elliot wong?
他转去研究高能量辐射
He switched over to high-energy radiation research,
出了一点事  现在谁坐到他旁边
Had a little mishap, and now the other guys
都会感到有点不舒服
Are uncomfortable sitting next to him.
-你来吗  -好啊  干吗不来
-you're in? -yeah, sure, why not?
好极了  我们周二到你那儿排练
Great, we rehearse on tuesdays at your place.
为什么来我那儿
Why at my place?
能源系说我们平常待的地方基本可以算是个断字区
Department of energy said our regular space is kind of a hot zone.
-很高兴见到你  -我也是
-nice meeting you. -yeah, you, too.
里奥纳德  我不知道你还会拉大提琴啊
Leonard. I didn't know you played the cello.
是的  我父母嫌给我取名为里奥纳德
Yeah, my parents felt that naming me leonard
并把我扔进大学先修班(考试合格大学可不再修读)
And putting me in advanced placement classes
还不够把我给打倒
Wasn't getting me beaten up enough.
如果你钟情音乐  我正好擅长口技
If you're into music, I happen to be a human beatbox.
真的?
Really?
事实上我不那么钟情音乐
I'm actually not that into music.
你朋友很不错啊
Your friend's really cute.
你们俩之间有发生什么吗
Anything going on with you two?
你说莱斯莉?
Leslie?
不  不会
No, no.
-开什么玩笑  -他曾经约过她
-what, are you kidding? -he asked her out once.
不过尴尬地失败了
It was an embarrassing failure.
-谢谢  谢尔顿  -抱歉
-thank you, sheldon. -i'm sorry.
这应该保密吗
Was that supposed to be a secret?
那太糟了  你们能成为挺般配的一对
That's too bad. you guys'd make a cute couple.
天啊
Oh, dear.
-什么事  -她没有让我点
-what's the matter? -she didn't take my order.
你那么神经质都不能跟她说话  你叫她怎么让你点
How can she take your order when you're too neurotic to talk to her?
不管怎样  这会反映在她的小费里
Nevertheless, this will be reflected in her tip.
潘妮说"你们能成为挺般配的一对"是什么意思
What did penny mean, "you'd make a cute couple?"
我估计她是说如果你们两个
I assume she meant the two of you together
走到一起成为一对  别人会觉得挺般配
Would constitute a couple that others might consider cute.
或者还有种可能性比较小的解释是
An alternate and somewhat less likely interpretation
你们能制造出很般配的一对(原话里make也可解释为制造)
Is that you could manufacture one.
就像在这句里"看  里奥纳德和莱斯莉制造了高德法布夫妇
As in, "look, leonard and leslie made mr. and mrs. goldfarb.
他们是不是很可爱"
Aren't they adorable?"
如果潘妮不知道莱斯莉拒绝过我
If penny didn't know that leslie had turned me down,
那她的话很明确是意思说
Then it would unambiguously mean
她(潘妮)认为我应该约她(莱斯莉)
That she, penny, thought I should ask her, leslie, out,
那就表明她(潘妮)对我约她(潘妮)完全没有兴趣
Indicating that she penny had no interest in me asking her, penny, out.
但是  因为她知道我曾经约过莱斯莉
But, because she did know that I had asked leslie out
而她(莱斯莉)拒绝了我  那她(潘妮)
And that she, leslie, had turned me down, then she, penny,
可能是在安慰我
Could be offering consolation.
"那太糟了  你们应该能成为挺般配的一对"
"that's too bad, you would have made a cute couple,"
但同时在想  "很好  里奥纳德还是单身"
but while thinking "good, leonard remains available."
你真的很幸运  里奥纳德
You're a lucky man, leonard.
-怎么说  -你倾诉的对象是西半球
-how so? -you're talking to one of the three men
三个有能力跟得上你思路的人之一
In the western hemisphere capable of following that train of thought.
那你怎么看?
Well, what do you think?
我说我跟得上  没说我关心
I said I could follow it. I didn't say I care.
你的指法令人称赞
I admire your fingering.
谢谢
Thank you.
或许什么时候你可以在我的乐器上试试
Maybe sometime you can try that on my instrument.
-晚安  伙计们  干得不错  -谢谢
-g'night, guys. good job. -thanks.
下周见
See you next week.
-很有意思  谢谢你叫上我  -不客气
-that was fun. thanks for including me. -you're welcome.
如果你还有兴趣  我们可以把中间部分再练一遍
If you're up for it, we could practice that middle section again.
好啊
Sure, why not?
为了表达地清楚些
Just so we're clear, you understand
你知道我留下来陪你练习只是托词
That me hanging back to practice with you
我是想让你知道你可以和我发生关系
Is a pretext for letting you know that I'm sexually available.
你说真的?
Really?
是  我已经准备好了
Yeah, I'm good to go.
我以为你对我没兴趣的
I thought you weren't interested in me.
那是因为之前我没见过你是怎么
That was before I saw you handling
把弄你两腿间那美丽的木头的
That beautiful piece of wood between your legs.
你是说大提琴?
You mean my cello?
不  我是说那个很明显的  粗俗的双关
No, I mean the obvious, crude, double entendre.
我正在色诱你
I'm seducing you.
开玩笑吧
No kidding.
该怎么说呢  我是个有激情又冲动的女人
What can I say? I'm a passionate and impulsive woman.
你觉得如何
So how about it?
天...
Gee. uh...
是因为那个服务生?
Is it the waitress?
潘妮?
Penny?
她怎么了
What about her?
你看着她时我好像发现你的瞳孔放大了
I thought I saw your pupils dilate when you looked at her.
除非你是吸毒上瘾  否则那就是由于性吸引了
Which, unless you're a heroin addict, points to sexual attraction.
我早饭的确吃了罂粟子面包圈
I did have a poppy seed bagel for breakfast.
鸦片成分可能引起尿检呈阳性
Which could cause a positive urine test for opiates,
但肯定不至于瞳孔放大
But certainly not dilate my pupils.
因此我感觉好像没必要说这些
So I guess there was no point in bringing it up.
那么你是和那位服务生
You and the waitress then.
不...没有
No... no.
我和潘妮之间没有任何事情发生
There's nothing going on between penny and me.
所以说你现在是可以发展一段性关系了?
So you're open to a sexual relationship?
是  是  我想是的
Yeah, yeah, I guess I am.
-好啊  -是  很好
-good. -yeah, it is. it is good.
你现在就想开始吗
Did you want to start now?
我们先完成这一段吧
Why don't we finish the section first?
来点音乐作为前戏  好极了
A little musical foreplay. terrific.
我准备好了
I'm good to go.
我也是
Me, too.
是谢尔顿啊  有什么事
Hey, sheldon. what's going on?
我有个符号学的问题想问问你
I need your opinion on a matter of semiotics.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
符号学  是研究符号和标记的科学
Semiotics. the study of signs and symbols.
是一门与语言学相关的哲学分支
It's a branch of philosophy related to linguistics.
亲爱的  我明白你认为你有在解释
Okay, sweetie, I know you think you're explaing yourself,
但你真的没有
But you're really not.
跟我来就是了
Just come with me.
-说  -说  说什么?
-well? -well, what?
这是什么意思
What does it mean?
得了  你可上过大学啊
Oh, come on, you went to college.
没错  可我那时才11岁
Yes, but I was 11.
好吧  看  门把上挂一条领带通常是说
All right, look, a tie on the doorknob usually means
里面的人不想被打扰
Someone doesn't want to be disturbed
因为  他们...正在忙
Because, they're... you know, gettin' busy.
你是说里奥纳德和一个女孩在里面?
So you're saying leonard has a girl in there?
要么是如此  要么就是他的领带架掉了
Well, either that or he's lost his tie rack
并且他真的钟情于布莱恩·亚当斯
And gotten really into bryan adams.
里奥纳德  你真是头猛兽
Oh, leonard, you magnificent beast.
我们真的不该站在这儿了
We really shouldn't be standing here.
真是尴尬
This is very awkward.
不会吧  里奥纳德以前也带女孩子回来过的  是吧
Oh, come on, leonard's had girls over before, right?
是  但通常总是计划好  奉承我一番  并且事先通知
Yes, but there's usually planning, courtship, advance notice...
上一次
Last time,
我订到了去北冰洋的航船  在那里看日食
I was able to book a cruise to the arctic to see a solar eclipse.
因为你的室友要做爱  你就得离开整个国土?
You had to leave the state because your roommate was having sex?
没有  是日期刚好碰上
I didn't have to. the dates just happened to coincide.
那么  你知道里面是谁吗
So, do you know who's in there?
里面有里奥纳德
Well, there's leonard.
其次他要么是和莱斯莉·温克尔  要么就是和30年代的黑帮
And he's either with Leslie Winkle or a 1930s gangster.
不错啊
Good for him.
恭喜里奥纳德
Good for Leonard.
好  晚安
Okay, g'night.
不  等等  慢点
No, no, wait, hold on.
有什么事?
What's the matter?
我不知道接下去的程序是怎么样的
I don't know what the protocol is here.
我该留在这儿  还是该离开这儿
Do I stay? Do I leave?
还是该等着拿杯清爽的饮料迎接他们
Do I wait to greet them with a refreshing beverage?
天哪  谢尔顿  你问错人了
Gee, Sheldon. You're asking the wrong girl.
我通常在领带的另一边
I'm usually on the other side of the tie.
好啊  里奥纳德
Hi, Leonard?
是我  谢尔顿...
It's me, Sheldon...
我在客厅
In the living room.
我...只是想告诉你我看到领带了
I just... I wanted you to know I saw the tie.
信号收到了
Message received.
不客气
You're welcome.
你继续
You carry on.
代我向莱斯莉问好
Give my best to Leslie.
"大块头"
Big boy...
有人动过我的板
Someone touched my board.
天哪  我的板!
Oh, god, my board!
里奥纳德  里奥纳德
Leonard! Leonard!
发生什么事了
Hey, what's the matter?
我的方程式  有人动了我的方程式
My equations, someone's tampered with my equations.
-你确定?  -我当然确定
-Are you sure? -Of course I am.
看这个量子色动力学的贝塔函数
Look at the beta function of quantum chromodynamics.
符号变掉了
The sign's been changed.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
不过那不是正好解决了你搞不懂的问题?
But doesn't that fix the problem you've been having?
你疯掉了?  你是不是脑子错乱了?
Are you insane? are you out of your mind?
你...  看!
Are you--look!
这正好解决了我搞不懂的问题
That fixes the problem I've been having.
不客气
You're welcome.
这是你干的?
You did this?
是  我过去拿水喝的时候注意到了  所以就改了下
Yeah. I noticed it when I got up to get a glass of water. so I fixed it.
很酷吧
Pretty cool, huh?
"酷"?
"cool"?
这样  我得先去实验室了  昨晚很美妙  谢谢
Listen, I've got to get to the lab. thanks for a great night.
谢谢  待会学校见
Thank you. I'll see you at work.
慢点  慢点!
Hold on. hold on!
-怎么?  -谁告诉你可以随便动我板了
-what? -who told you you could touch my board?
没有人
No one.
我可不会到你房间去动你的板
I don't come into your house and touch your board.
因为我的板上不会有错误的方程式
There are no incorrect equations on my board.
你真是太...
Oh, that is so...
太...
So...
抱歉  我赶时间  如果你想到了形容词  发消息给我
Sorry, I've got to run. if you come up with an adjective, text me.
不顾他人的
Inconsiderate.
就是这个词  "不顾他人的"
That is the adjective, "inconsiderate. "
你可以一整天都盯着那块板  谢尔顿  可她还是正确的
You can stare at your board all day, sheldon. she's still going to be right.
我没有盯着看  我在闭目沉思呢
I'm not staring, I'm mulling.
-好啊  里奥纳德  -你好
-Hey, Leonard. -Hi
你...
So...
干得怎么样啊
How's it going?
还不错
Pretty good.
只是还不错?  我觉得是非常不错
Just pretty good? I'd think you were doing very good.
"还"  "非常"  其实没有什么客观尺度
Pretty, very... there's really no objective scale
来划定"不错"的程度  你为什么问?
For delineating variations of "good." why do you ask?
有只小鸟告诉我说
Well, a little bird told me
你和莱斯莉昨晚搞上了
That you and Leslie hooked up last night.
谢尔顿!
Sheldon!
来了
I'm coming.
那么  你是认真的吗  你喜欢她?
So, is it serious? do you like her?
我不...
I don't...
这是两个非常不同的问题
That's really two different questions.
我...
I'm not...
谢尔顿  我们得走了!
Sheldon, we have to go!
对一个刚进行过性交的人来说  你实在是出奇地紧张啊
You're wound awfully tight for a man who's just had sexual intercourse.
好了  以后再说  不过我为你感到高兴  里奥纳德
All right, I'll talk to you later, but I am so happy for you, Leonard.
谢谢
Thank you.
她为我感到高兴是什么意思?
What did she mean she's happy for me?
因为我有了约会她感到高兴?
Is she happy because I'm seeing someone?
或是她认为我很高兴  所以她感到高兴?
Or is she happy because she thinks that I am happy?
因为任何人如果关心某人都想要那人高兴
Because anyone who cared for someone would want them to be happy.
即使是那人高兴的理由让前者感到并不高兴
Even if the reason for their happiness made the first person unhappy.
因为后者  虽然高兴
Because the second person, though happy,
但却和前者再无发展浪漫关系的可能了
Is now romantically unavailable to the first person.
你有意识到我可能要和你那位"应招小姐"分享诺贝尔奖了吗
Do you realize I may have to share a nobel prize with your booty call?
你猜我怎么想
You know what?
我真是太荒唐了
I'm being ridiculous.
我管潘妮她是怎么想
Who cares what penny thinks?
莱斯莉是个很好的女孩  她有魅力
Leslie is a terrific girl. she's attractive.
我们喜欢彼此  她惊人得聪明...
We like each other. she's extremely intelligent...
-她没那么聪明  -她解决了你的方程式
-she's not that intelligent. -she fixed your equation.
-她走运而已  -你可从不相信运气的
-she got lucky. -you don't believe in luck.
我没必要因为她走运就相信运气
I don't have to believe in it for her to be lucky.
不管怎样  我现在有机会和莱斯莉发展一段真正的恋情
Regardless, I have a chance at a real relationship with leslie.
我不会就这么放弃
I'm not going to pass that up
就为了一个可能和她有幸福未来的女人
For some hypothetical future of happiness with a woman
一个可能想  也可能不想让我幸福的女人
Who may or may not want me to be happy,
而放弃了一个现在就已经让我幸福的女人
With a woman who is currently making me happy.
-里奥纳德  -什么
Leonard. Yeah?
我仍然不关心
I still don't care.
好啊  莱斯莉
Hey leslie.
小心  里奥纳德  液态氮  零下320度
Careful, leonard. liquid nitrogen, 320 degrees below zero.
为什么你要打碎一只速冻香蕉?
Why are you smashing a flash-frozen banana?
因为我有一碗麦片  又找不到刀来切
because I got a bowl of cheerios and I couldn't find a knife.
那不管它...
So anyway...
你好啊
Hello.
你在干吗
What are you doing?
更加亲密点喽
Just extending the intimacy.
想不想溜进放射实验室里
Do you want to slip over to the radiation lab
共享净化澡?
And share a decontamination shower?
好吧...
Ok, uh...
你认为我们之间到底怎么回事?
What exactly do you think's going on between us?
我不确定  但我认为我马上就要体会那香蕉的感受了
I'm not sure, but I think I'm about to discover how the banana felt.
听着  里奥纳德  我们虽然都不是神经学家
Listen, Leonard. neither of us are neuroscientists,
但我们都懂得性的生化机理
But we both understand the biochemistry of sex.
我是说  我们脑中的多巴胺
I mean, dopamine in our brains
通过突触被释放了  从而产生了快感
Is released across synapses, causing pleasure.
你把电极插到老鼠的大脑里  给他一个性高潮按钮
You stick electrodes in a rat's brain, give him an orgasm button,
他会一直按那东西直到饿死为止
He'll push that thing until he starves to death.
谁不会呢
Well, who wouldn't?
我们和老鼠的唯一区别就在于
Well, the only difference between us and the rat
我们不能把一个电极插到我们的下丘脑里
Is that you can't stick an electrode in our hypothalamus.
所以你就出现了
That's where you come in.
是啊  我很高兴参与其中
Yeah, well, I'm just glad to be a part of it.
那现在怎样
So what happens now?
我不清楚你的性欲怎样  我反正到新年之前应该都可以了
I don't know about your sex drive, but I'm probably good till new year's.
-谢谢你  -谢谢你
-thank you. -thank you.
你想计划下新年的安排吗
You want to make plans for new year's?
拜托了  你要噎着我了
Please. you're smothering me.
看啊  是猛男博士啊!
Look. it's dr. stud!
啥博士?
Dr. what?
博客圈正不断更新着你和莱斯莉·温克尔
The blogosphere is a-buzzin' with news of you and leslie winkle
合作G大调弦乐小嘭嘭夜曲的新闻呢
Making eine kleine bang-bang musik.
怎么会弄到网上去的?
How did it get on the internet?
我放上去的
I put it there.
你怎么会知道的?
How did you know about it?
有只小鸟告诉我们的
A little bird told us.
很明显  你真是头猛兽
Apparently, you are a magnificent beast.
这个倒是没错
That part's true.
我想我之前可能误解这家餐厅了
I think I may have misjudged this restaurant.
-真的假的  -我不想出去时候很尴尬
-no kidding. -i don't want to go out on a limb,
不过我认为我们看到了我的新周二汉堡
But I think we may be looking at my new tuesday hamburger.
你的老周二汉堡会伤心欲绝的
Your old Tuesday hamburger will be so broken-hearted.
我早就想到了  我考虑把"大块头"放到周四
Way ahead of you. I was thinking of moving Big Boy to Thursdays,
然后放弃"种汤餐馆"
And just dropping souplantation.
说真的
Really?
反正那名字总是让我搞不懂  种汤
The name always confused me anyway. souplantation.
汤又不能种
You can't grow soup.
一切还好吗
So, how's everything?
好极了  你应该会很高兴
Terrific. you'll be happy to know that I plan to come here
因为我准备在可预见的每周二晚都来这里
Every tuesday night for the foreseeable future.
是吗  好啊
Really? Oh, yea.
如果我要永久预定这桌子我该找谁说
Who do I speak to about permanently reserving this table?
我不知道...找精神病医生?
I don't know... a psychiatrist?
你和莱斯莉怎么样了啊
How are things with you and leslie?
老实交待  我认为我们没戏了
To be honest, I don't think it's going to work out.
那太糟糕了
Oh, that's too bad.
别担心
Hey, don't worry.
我确定会有人真正适合你的
I'm sure there's someone out there who's just right for you.
她那话什么意思?!
What did she mean by that?!
只是句普通的安慰呢
Was that just a generic platitude,
还是为了让我引起注意的微妙暗示?
Or was that a subtle bid for attention?
你知道为什么这个汉堡会超过"大块头"
You know why this hamburger surpasses the big boy?
这是个单层汉堡  大块头是双层的
This is a single-decker hamburger, whereas the big boy is a double-decker.
这个汉堡的肉  面包  佐料更另人满意
This has a much more satisfying meat-to-bun-to-condiment ratio.
你有在听我说吗
Are you even listening to me?
当然  我在听  什么什么对于潘妮不可救药的妄想...
Of course, I'm listening. blah, blah, hopeless penny delusion...
好吧那
Okay, then.
知道吗  做汤用的食材是可以种的
You know, you can grow the ingredients for soup.